linkme.com.au 2018-11-20

# LiveHire - Australia's 1st labour market, where workers and employers connect directly

##  Privacy Policy LiveHire's Privacy policy was last modified on: 25 May 2018

**G'day, welcome to LiveHire!**

This Privacy Policy and our Terms and Conditions help guide decisions we make every day in our company, so we can help protect and empower the flow of the world's talent through organisations, to create a more agile, open and awesome working world. 

For the purposes of this Privacy Policy, when we say **"Users"** , **"you"** or **"your"** we mean any individuals about whom we process personal information from time to time including any persons creating an account on our Platform, users of our website, applicants for employment, Customers and all other persons who may provide personal information to us from time to time. 

**Important information about LiveHire**

Words like **"us"** , **"we"** , **"our"** , **"LiveHire"** or **"LiveHire.com"** refer to LiveHire Ltd of Level 10, 461 Bourke Road, Melbourne, Victoria 3000 (ABN 59 153 266 605) (https://www.livehire.com). LiveHire is a cloud-based human resources productivity platform for sourcing and recruitment that delivers ‘talent on demand' for small to large enterprises. The Platform enables Customers to leverage their brand, employee networks and digital assets to invite and curate talent from anywhere, online and offline into a private ‘Talent Community'. It also allows individuals to sign up to our Platform and to source new opportunities with small to large enterprises in our network. 

As LiveHire will be responsible for originally collecting personal information about you, LiveHire will be your primary Data Controller. 

You can find out more about LiveHire at https://www.livehire.com or by contacting us here. 

As we are an international organisation, providing our services in multiple jurisdictions, some country-specific requirements may apply as set out in this Privacy Policy. 

As you use our Services, we want you to be clear about how we collect and use your information, the ways in which you can protect your information at all times and how we help you in protecting your information. 

This Privacy Policy explains how we collect, use and share personal information in the course of our business activities, including: 

  * What information do we collect and when do we collect it 
  * Use of personal information 
  * Legal basis for using your personal information 
  * Direct marketing 
  * Accessing, correcting and updating your personal information 
  * Information we share 
  * International transfers 
  * Application 
  * How long do we keep your personal information? 
  * Security 
  * Enforcement and Complaints 
  * Changes 
  * Contact us 

Your privacy matters to us, so whether you are new to the Platform or a long-term User, please do take the time to get to know our practices and read through this Privacy Policy and if you have any questions please contact us. 

If you require a copy of this Privacy Policy in a particular form, please let us know and we will arrange to provide this to you. 

###  What information do we collect and when do we collect it 

####  Information gathered during registration 

When you sign up for our Services, or register to use our Platform as a User, we collect and process certain personal information and data on you which includes: 

  * If you are a **Worker** : information relating to your resume or CV including in respect of your work (i.e. industry and operations, profession and specialties, work history) education and qualifications, contact details including your name (first, last and middle name, where applicable), address, city, state, zip/postal code, country, email address, and date of birth, profile data (including password and username, log-ins), technical data (IP address, browser type, other technology on the device used) and usage data), including on the frequency of your use of our Platform and Website(s), each as further detailed below. We also collect marketing and communications data, including your preferences for receiving marketing and related communications from us. 
  * If you are a **Customer** : we will collect certain data (which is not personal data) in order to provide our Services to you and your users, including your business or company name, and payment information. If you are an individual representative of the Customer with whom we engage in offering and providing our Services, we will also collect your contact details and marketing and communications' preferences. 

We may, in the future, include other optional requests for information from you, to help us update, improve or tailor the Platform for you and/or deliver personalised information to you. You do not have to provide any additional personal information and can opt out of any such request for information at any time from us by clicking ‘unsubscribe' on any of the relevant communications from us or by emailing us at [privacy@livehire.com](mailto:privacy@livehire.com). Any information you do choose to provide to us will be held and protected by us in accordance with the terms of this Privacy Policy. 

We collect personal information through various means, including our website(s), social media pages, phone calls with you, forms completed by you or other correspondence with you. In some circumstances, we collect information about you from publicly accessible sources, such as Facebook and LinkedIn. For example, we may collect your personal information when you: 

  * create an Account on our Platform; 
  * complete and provide an Application to us; 
  * as a corporate customer, provide personal information to comply with our AML (anti-money laundering) processes; 
  * request information or material from us; 
  * make a donation; 
  * enter one of our promotions; 
  * subscribe to our mailing list; and/or 
  * join our social media pages. 

####  Information from third parties 

We may also collect personal information about you from third parties and publicly available sources. We may keep a record of your use of the Platform or Services and any communication between you and us. 

If at any time you provide the personal information of another person to us, then you must ensure that, and we will assume, that person has read, understands and acknowledges the terms of this Privacy Policy. We will treat and protect that person's information in the same way as set out in this Privacy Policy. 

####  Sensitive Data 

Sometimes we may collect sensitive information including Sensitive Personal Data if you choose to disclose this to us or as part of providing Services to you. 

Your provision of Sensitive Personal Data to us is optional and we will never collect this data unless you choose to provide it. You do not have to provide this information to receive our Services. If you choose to provide it, Sensitive Personal Data which we may collect from you, with your prior consent, may include information on your gender, nationality and ethnicity (only if you are an Australian citizen or resident) which we may request for the purposes of verifying work permits and visa requirements and to support diversity initiatives that may arise in connection with our provision of the Services. 

We will not use sensitive information for any secondary purpose, unless you would reasonably expect the information to be used for the secondary purpose, and that secondary purpose is directly related to the primary purpose of collection and you have consented to that further use. 

We do not collect Sensitive Personal Data on EU / UK individuals. However, if you are a UK or EU individual or resident in the EU or UK before ever collecting and/or using any Sensitive Personal Data we will establish a lawful exemption which will allow us to use that information. This exemption will typically be: 

  * your explicit consent; 
  * the establishment, exercise or defence by us or third parties of legal claims; 

####  Usage Data 

We may collect information about the Services you use and how you use them and/or the Platform. This usage data and information includes: 

  * Device information We may collect device-specific information (such as your hardware model, operating system version, unique device identifiers, and mobile network information including phone number). We may associate your device identifiers or phone number with your Account. We also automatically collect your browser type and browser software version to optimize the presentation of the Platform to your platform and to maintain a record of your activity on the Platform. Please see our Cookies Policy for further information on how we collect and process browser type information and your rights to opt-out of this. 
  * Log information When you use our Services or view content provided by us (including through our General Search function), we may automatically collect and store certain information in our server logs. This may include: 
    * Details of how you used the Service, such as search queries 
    * Telephony log information 
    * Internet Protocol (IP) address. As an automatic process, our webserver records a log file of IP addresses that access the Platform. We also collect IP address and other system information for purposes of statistical analysis and to maintain the trust and security of the Platform. We will not use IP addresses or other system information to identify a User unless we determine, in our sole discretion, that it is necessary to improve our services or to enforce compliance with our policies or agreements with Users to protect our Service, Platform, Customers and others. Notwithstanding this, we gather only that information that is reasonably necessary for us to operate and improve the Platform and otherwise conduct our business. We use commercially reasonable efforts to ensure our collection of information does not interfere with the operation or security of your system. 
    * Device event information such as crashes, system activity, hardware settings, browser type, browser language, the date and time of your request and referral URL. 
    * We use [Hotjar](https://www.hotjar.com/) in order to better understand our users' needs and to optimize this service and experience. Hotjar is a technology service that helps us better understand our users experience (e.g. how much time they spend on which pages, which links they choose to click, what users do and don't like, etc.) and this enables us to build and maintain our service with user feedback. Hotjar uses cookies and other technologies to collect data on our users' behaviour and their devices (in particular device's IP address (captured and stored only in anonymized form), device screen size, device type (unique device identifiers), browser information, geographic location (country only), preferred language used to display our website). Hotjar stores this information in a pseudonymized user profile. Neither Hotjar nor we will ever use this information to identify individual users or to match it with further data on an individual user. For further details, please see Hotjar's privacy policy by clicking on [this link](https://www.hotjar.com/legal/policies/privacy). You can opt-out to the creation of a user profile, Hotjar's storing of data about your usage of our site and Hotjar's use of tracking cookies on other websites by following this [opt-out](https://www.hotjar.com/legal/compliance/opt-out) link. 
  * Location information When you use a location-enabled service or device, we may collect and process information about your location. We may also use various technologies to determine location, such as sensor data from your device and IP addresses. We collect this data in order to pre-complete forms for you, and to allow relevant suggestions of job opportunities. 
  * Unique application numbers Certain Services include a unique application number. This number and information about your installation (for example, the operating system type and application version number) may be sent to us when you install or uninstall that Service or when that service periodically contacts our servers, such as for automatic updates. 
  * Local storage We may collect and store information, including personal information, locally on your device using mechanisms such as browser web storage (including HTML 5) and application data caches. 
  * Cookies and anonymous identifiers We use various technologies to collect and store information when you visit our Platform, including cookies, which are a small text file containing small amounts of information which is downloaded to/stored on your computer (or other internet enabled devices, such as a smartphone or tablet) when you visit a website. Cookies may collect personal information about you. Cookies help us remember information about your visit to our website, like your country, language and other settings. Cookies allow us to understand who has seen which webpages and advertisements, to determine how frequently particular pages are visited and to determine the most popular areas of our website. They can also help us to operate our website more efficiently and make your next visit easier. 
  * We may send one or more cookies or anonymous identifiers to your device. We also use cookies and anonymous identifiers when you interact with Services we offer through our partners, such as validation services, or Platform features that may appear on other websites. We may use persistent cookies (which remain on your computer even after you close your browser) to store information that may speed up your use of our website for any of your future visits to the website. 
  * We may also use session cookies (which no longer remain after you end your browsing session) to help manage the display and presentation of information on the website. Certain third parties (including, for example, advertising networks and providers of external services like web traffic analysis services) may also use cookies, over which we have no control. These cookies are likely to be analytical/performance cookies or targeting cookies. You should review the privacy policies of such third parties to understand how they use and protect your personal data. 
  * We will not combine DoubleClick cookie information with personal information as per the terms of our Cookies Policy. 

You always have the option of disabling cookies via your browser preferences. If you disable cookies on your browser, please note that some parts of our Platform may not function as effectively or may be considerably slower. Please see our Cookies Policy for more information on how we use cookies when you access our services or use our website(s). If you have any question on the use of cookies on our site, please do not hesitate to contact us. 

###  What we use your personal information for 

We use the personal information we collect from your use of our Services, from information you enter on the Platform, and information gathered during registration for a number of purposes, including to: 

  * enable us to provide, maintain, protect and improve the Services and our products offered to you, to operate our business and develop new services, and to help us protect you and the Platform; 
  * offer you specific and relevant information – like search results, IOPS, work opportunities and education recommendations - in connection with the provision of our Services; 
  * assist you in pursuing potential employment opportunities with or through LiveHire Customers as part of our Services; 
  * as required by law and when complying with our legal obligations and assisting governments and law enforcement agencies or regulators (as required by law); 
  * support our internal business purposes (including administration, planning, product development); 
  * Based on your preferences, issue marketing materials, including promotions and fundraising to you; and 
  * contact you to inform you about updates to the Platform and Services and provide information relating to transactions you may conduct on the Platform. 

We will never rent, sell or provide your personal information to third parties except as set out in this Policy or we are otherwise required to disclose the information under applicable laws. 

We may combine personal information from our Services with information including personal information from our other services provided to you or from a Customer or Third Party Service Provider and/or Other Third Parties for the purposes of ensuring we can deliver our Services to you, for example to provide Verification to your resume data and personal information provided to us. We will only do so this accordance with the terms set out in this Policy. 

###  Legal basis for using your personal information 

####  For EU/UK individuals: 

If you are an individual who is either based in or a resident of the European Union or the United Kingdom, we will only collect, use and share your personal information where we are satisfied that we have an appropriate legal basis to do this. We will make sure that we only use your personal information for the purposes set out above and in Appendix 2 where we are satisfied that: 

  * you have provided your consent to us using the data in that way; or 
  * our use of your personal information is necessary to perform the Services under the Terms and Conditions which you have executed with us or in order to take steps at your request prior to your entering into those Terms and Conditions with us; or 
  * our use of your personal information is necessary to comply with a relevant legal or regulatory obligation that we are subject to; or 
  * our use of your personal information is necessary to support the 'legitimate interests' that we have as a business, provided it is conducted at all times in a way that is proportionate, and that respects your privacy rights. In all such cases, we will look after your information at all times in a way that is proportionate and respects your privacy rights and you have a right to object to this processing as explained further in Appendix 2. 

If you would like to find out more about the legal basis for which we process personal information, please contact us. 

###  Direct marketing 

We may use your personal information to send you direct marketing communications about the Services or our related services. This may be in the form of email, post, SMS, telephone or targeted online advertisements This may also include email communications, including information that we think may be of interest to you, and information on upcoming changes or improvements. 

In most cases our processing of your personal information for marketing purposes is based on our legitimate interests, although in some cases (such as where required by applicable laws or where we use or process any of your Sensitive Personal information or Sensitive Data) it may be based on your explicit consent. You can find out more on how we process your Sensitive Personal Data and Sensitive Information above. 

You have a right to prevent direct marketing of any form at any time - this can be exercised by following the opt-out links in electronic communications, or contact us. When you receive any permitted electronic marketing communications from us, you may opt out of receiving further marketing communications by following the opt-out instructions provided in the communication. Please specify whether you would like us to stop all forms of marketing or just a particular type (e.g. email). 

You can also change the way your browser manages cookies, which may be used to deliver online advertising, by following the settings on your browser. See further our Cookies section above and our Cookies Policy. 

####  For EU/UK individuals: When and how we carry out profiling and automated decision making 

We do not conduct any automated decision-making on your personal information. We may use limited profiling or other forms of automated processing for: 

  * security purposes only to assess if your account may be fraudulent, a spam account or suspect in any way; 
  * the purposes of marketing, and where this is completed we undertake to do this to pursue our legitimate interests of ensuring our marketing communications are relevant to you, its audience and persons to whom it is targeted. 

As profiling uses automated processing, it is sometimes connected with automated decision making. Not all profiling results in automated decision making, but it can do. 

Please note, you have certain rights (including a right to object) in respect of automated decision making, where that decision has significant effects on you, including where it produces a legal effect on you. See below for more information about your rights. 

###  Accessing, correcting and updating your personal information 

To request access to personal information we hold about you, please contact us. If that information is incorrect, out of date or incomplete, we strive to give you ways to update it quickly or to delete it – unless we have to keep that information for legitimate business or legal purposes. When requesting access or changes to your personal information, we may ask you to verify your identity before we act on your request. 

There are some circumstances in which we are not required to give you access to your personal information. We may reject requests that are unlawful, frivolous, vexatious, unreasonably repetitive, require disproportionate technical effort (for example, developing a new system or fundamentally changing existing practices), that we believe risk the privacy, health or safety of others, or would be otherwise be extremely impractical (for example requests concerning information on our backup systems or unique ID data on Users). 

Where we provide information access and correction, we will do so for free, except where in our opinion it would require a disproportionate effort or cost for us to do so. We may require you to meet our reasonable costs in providing you with access including for photocopying and postage. 

Where you correct, update or otherwise provide personal information, you represent to us that the information you provide to us is, having regard to the circumstances, accurate, up to date and complete, having regard to the purposes of the disclosure, and not misleading or deceptive. We will respond to any requests to change your personal information within a reasonable timeframe and will take all reasonable steps to ensure that the personal information we hold about you remains accurate, up-to-date and complete. 

####  For EU/UK individuals 

If you are an individual based in or a resident of the European Union or the United Kingdom, there are additional rights to your personal data available to you. Please see below your detailed rights including rights of access, erasure, rectification and portability of your personal data. 

Right  |  What this means   
---|---  
Access |  You can ask us to: 

  * confirm whether we are processing your personal information; 
  * give you a copy of that data; 
  * provide you with other information about your personal information such as what data we have, what we use it for, who we disclose it to, whether we transfer it abroad and how we protect it, how long we keep it for, what rights you have, how you can make a complaint, where we got your data from, to the extent that information has not already been provided to you in this Privacy Policy. 

Rectification  |  You can ask us to rectify inaccurate personal information. We may seek to verify the accuracy of the data before rectifying it.   
Erasure  |  You can ask us to erase your personal information, but only where: 

  * it is no longer needed for the purposes for which it was collected; or 
  * you have withdrawn your consent (where the data processing was based on consent); or 
  * following a successful right to object (see 'Objection' below); or 
  * it has been processed unlawfully; or 
  * to comply with a legal obligation to which LiveHire is subject. 

We are not required to comply with your request to erase your personal information if the processing of your personal information is necessary: 

  * for compliance with a legal obligation; or 
  * for the establishment, exercise or defence of legal claims. 

Restriction  |  You can ask us to restrict (i.e. keep but not use) your personal information, but only where: 

  * its accuracy is contested (see Rectification), to allow us to verify its accuracy; or 
  * the processing is unlawful, but you do not want it erased; or 
  * it is no longer needed for the purposes for which it was collected, but we still need it to establish, exercise or defend legal claims; or 
  * you have exercised the right to object, and verification of overriding grounds is pending. 

We can continue to use your personal information following a request for restriction, where: 
  * we have your consent; 
  * to establish, exercise or defend legal claims; or 
  * to protect the rights of another natural or legal person. 

Portability  |  You can ask us to provide your personal information to you in a structured, commonly used, machine-readable format but case only where: 

  * the processing is based on your consent or on the performance of a contract with you; and 
  * the processing is carried out by automated means. 

Objection  |  You can object to any processing of your personal information which has our 'legitimate interests' as its legal basis, if you believe your fundamental rights and freedoms outweigh our legitimate interests. Once you have objected, we have an opportunity to demonstrate that we have compelling legitimate interests which override your rights and freedoms.   
International transfers  |  You can ask to obtain a copy of, or reference to, the safeguards under which your personal information is transferred outside of the European Economic Area. We may redact data transfer agreements or related documents (i.e. obscure certain information contained within these documents) for reasons of commercial sensitivity.   
Supervisory Authority  |  You have a right to lodge a complaint with your local supervisory authority about our processing of your personal information. For example, in the UK, the supervisory authority for data protection is the [ICO ](https://ico.org.uk/). We ask that you please attempt to resolve any issues with us first, although you have a right to contact your supervisory authority at any time.   
  
If you wish to access any of the above mentioned rights, we may ask you for additional information to confirm your identity and for security purposes, in particular before disclosing personal information to you. We reserve the right to charge a fee where permitted by law, for instance if your request is manifestly unfounded or excessive. 

We may not always be able to fully address your request, for example if it would impact the duty of confidentiality we owe to others, or if we are legally entitled to deal with the request in a different way. 

###  Information we share / disclose to other parties 

We do not share your personal information with any other Person unless one of the following circumstances applies: 

  * **Customers** : we share personal information with our Customers, including user profile details such as your full CV, verification details, LinkedIn or Facebook data, and other personal data you have provided when you apply to connect to or accept an invitation to connect from a Customer or join a LiveHire talent community (a ' **Connection** '). We ensure the protection of your personal information at all times and we have agreements in place with all our Customers to maintain your rights on privacy in a similar way to the protections afforded under this Privacy Policy. You are in full control of the privacy settings on your account on the LiveHire Platform. This gives you full control of your personal information, including to update your information, and if desired, discontinue sharing that information with specific Customers by deactivating the Connection 
  * If you are a UK/EU individual based in or resident in the EU/UK, when a Customer contacts you or requests additional information from you for its own purposes (for example for the purposes of inviting you for interview for a role), the information you provide directly to Customer pursuant to such request will be held and processed by that Customer in accordance with their own privacy policy and terms. You should therefore request a copy of and familiarise yourself with the terms and privacy policy of any Customer with whom you wish to engage further. 
  * **Third Party Service Providers** : we provide your information to Third Party Service Providers to help manage our business and deliver services. These include IT service providers who help manage our IT and back office systems including the hosting and storage of personal data, as well as email and SMS service providers. Some of these providers use 'cloud based' IT applications or systems, which means that your personal data will be hosted on their servers, but under our control and direction. We require all our third party service providers to respect the confidentiality, privacy and security of personal data and our contracts with them include obligations for them to comply with applicable privacy laws and to use any personal information we share with them solely for the purpose of providing services to us. 
  * **Other Third Parties** \- we also provide your information to other third parties for the purposes of ensuring that we can provide our full Services to you and to our Customers. These third party recipients broadly include the categories of Verification providers (who process your personal data for the purposes of analysing, verifying and validating references, qualification and police records as contained in your CV or provided under your account with us, including verifying your legal rights to work or carry on services in the jurisdiction in which you are located or choose to work), CV parsing technology providers (who access and process your information and use parsing technology for the purposes of analysing and producing a structured profile for you) and other third party providers who enable us to carry out our Services and improve our Services to you (including for example for the purposes of conducting video interviews and conferences). We require and ensure all our third parties to whom we disclose or share your personal information respect the confidentiality, privacy and security of this information and our contracts with these third parties include obligations for them to comply with applicable privacy laws and to use any personal information we share with them solely for the purpose of providing services to us. . 
  * **For legal reasons** : we may share or limit access to your personal information if we have a good-faith belief that access, use, preservation or disclosure of, or restriction therefrom, the information is reasonably necessary to comply with any applicable legal, regulatory or other administrative or governmental process, enquiry or action, enforce our Agreement with you or investigate any potential breach, detect, prevent, or otherwise address any potential fraud, security or technical issues, or protect against potential harm to the rights, property or safety of our Users, us or the public. We may also disclose personal information where we are required to do so by applicable laws. 
  * **Restructure of our Business** \- If we are involved in or contemplate a merger, acquisition, asset sale, corporate restructure or other similar transaction, we may disclose certain information regarding the Platform and the Services, which may include personal information, to potential purchasers or investors for our legitimate business purposes. We will do so subject to acceptable confidentiality obligations being granted to us. 
  * **Anonymised/ Aggregated Information** : We may use and disclose to any person any de-identified information (not personally identifiable on its own or in combination with any other information held by us) we obtain from Users' use of the Platform, including statistical information of your use of our Services which is in aggregated and anonymised form. LiveHire will only use and disclose fully anonymised and de-identified statistical data information which is not personal information for the purposes of and in accordance with all applicable privacy laws. 

###  International transfers 

Your personal information may be disclosed, transferred to or processed outside of your country of residence including to Australia, New Zealand, the United States, the Philippines and Singapore. Your personal information is principally maintained within data centres and servers located in Australia. 

When you connect with Customers for employment opportunities, the information shared with those customers may be processed in the countries in which they operate which may be outside of Australia. We take measures (including contractual commitments from LiveHire) to ensure that any disclosure of your personal information outside of Australia is completed in compliance with Australian Privacy laws. 

####  For EU/UK Individuals: 

If you are an individual based in or a resident of the European Union or the United Kingdom, your data may be processed outside of the European Union in countries, including in Australia, New Zealand, the United States, the Philippines and Singapore. that are subject to different standards of data protection. 

We will take appropriate steps ensure that transfers of personal information are in accordance with applicable law and carefully managed to protect your privacy rights and interests and transfers are limited to countries which are recognised as providing an adequate level of legal protection or where we can be satisfied that alternative arrangements are in place to protect your privacy rights. To this end: 

  * although LiveHire is not currently part of a group of companies, we will ensure that in the event that LiveHire becomes part of a group of companies at any time, any transfers of your personal information between members of this group of companies will be covered by an agreement (an intra group agreement) which contractually obliges each member to ensure that personal information it receives is adequate and consistent level of protection wherever it is transferred within the group of companies; 
  * where we transfer your personal information outside any future group of companies or to third parties who help provide our Services, we obtain contractual commitments from them to protect your personal information. Some of these assurances are well recognized certification schemes like the **EU / US 'Privacy Shield'** for the protection of personal information transferred from within the EU to the United States and /or the use of EU approached Standard Contractual Clauses (' **EU Model Clauses** ') for controller to controller and /or controller to processor transfers from the EU /UK to jurisdictions, such as Australia and/or New Zealand, the United States, the Philippines and Singapore, who do not have an adequacy finding from the EU Commission ; and/or 
  * where we receive requests for information from law enforcement or regulators, we carefully validate these requests before any personal information are disclosed. 

You have a right to contact us for more information about the safeguards we have put in place (including a copy of relevant contractual commitments) to ensure the adequate protection of your personal information when this is transferred as mentioned above. 

###  Application 

Our Privacy Policy applies to all of the Services provided by us. 

####  Links to other sites 

Our Privacy Policy does not apply to services offered by other companies or individuals who are not LiveHire, including products or sites that may be displayed to you in search results, sites that may include our Services, or other sites linked to or from our Services. Our Privacy Policy does not cover the information practices of other companies and organisations who use our services, and who may use cookies, pixel tags and other technologies to serve and offer advertisements and information. Please see the associated privacy policies of such other third party websites or links for information on how these third parties process your personal information. 

Many of our Services also let you share information with others. Remember that when you share information publicly – like on Facebook, Linked-in or any blog – it may be indexable by search engines, such as Google. 

We are not responsible for the privacy practices or the content of any other websites to which the Platform links or which link to the Platform. By clicking on a link, logo or other item, please note that you may no longer be on the Platform. To check what Internet location you are on, always note the URL at the top and/or bottom of your browser. We encourage you to read the posted privacy statement of any website whenever interacting with it. 

###  How long do we keep your personal information? 

We will retain your personal information for as long as is reasonably necessary for the purposes for which we collect this information. In some limited circumstances we may retain your personal information for longer periods of time, for instance where we are required to do so in accordance with legal, regulatory, tax or accounting requirements. 

In specific circumstances we may also retain your personal information for longer periods of time so that we have an accurate record of your dealings with us in the event of any complaints or challenges, or if we reasonably believe there is a prospect of litigation relating to your personal information or dealings. We aim to maintain our Services in a manner that protects information from accidental or malicious destruction. At the request of any Customer or Worker, all data belonging to the requesting party can be removed from the system. 

For EU / UK individuals: To determine the appropriate retention periods, we consider the amount, nature and sensitivity of the personal data potential risk of harm from unauthorised use or disclosures the purposes for which we process your personal information and whether we can achieve those purposes through other means and the applicable legal requirements. In some circumstances we may store your personal information for longer periods of time than others, for instance where we are required to do so in accordance with legal, regulatory, tax, accounting requirements. This may be for a seven (7) year period unless the applicable law prescribes otherwise. If you would like more information on how we retain your data, please contact us. 

###  Security 

We recognise our responsibility to protect the personal information that you entrust to us. We take security very seriously and work together with you, developers and external security experts to design security into our products from the ground up (including through implementing privacy by design and security by design measures. 

We store most information about you in computer systems and databases operated by either us or our external cloud Service Providers. Some information about you may be recorded in paper files that we store securely. Our information storage is on secure computers in locked information centres and data is encrypted, wherever possible. However, as the transmission of information across the internet is not completely secure we cannot guarantee the security of your information transmitted to our website and issues can arise. 

We will also take reasonable steps to destroy or de-identify personal information once we no longer require it for the purposes for which it was collected or for any secondary purpose permitted under the Australian Privacy laws and/or other applicable data privacy laws. 

We recommend that you create a secure password, do not disclose your password and account details to anyone, and that you change your password each month. As the security of information depends in part on the security of the computer or device you use to communicate with us and the security you use to protect your user IDs and passwords, we encourage you to please take appropriate measures to protect this information. 

Our Platform is operated using security measures, including SSL (Secure Sockets Layer) encryption, to protect your personal data. SSL is an industry standard encryption protocol, and this ensure that the information is reasonably protected against unauthorised interception. 

We also implement and maintain processes and security measures to protect personal information which we hold from misuse, interference or loss, and from unauthorised access, modification or disclosure. These processes and measures may include: 

  * requiring all employees to comply with internal information security policies and keep information secure; 
  * requiring all employees to complete training about information security; and 
  * monitoring and regularly reviewing our practices against our own policies and against industry best practice 

###  Enforcement and complaints 

We regularly review our compliance with this Privacy Policy as well as under applicable privacy laws. If you have a complaint regarding this policy or any breach of applicable privacy laws, please contact us immediately to register your complaint and let us know what we can do to resolve it. If we do receive your formal written complaint, we will contact respond to your complaint within a reasonable time and do everything reasonably practicable to resolve the complaint with you. 

We hope it won't ever come to this, but if you've already contacted us and feel that your complaint cannot be resolved between us, you can contact the relevant local [data protection supervisory authority](http://ec.europa.eu/newsroom/article29/item-detail.cfm?item_id=612080) (i.e. your place of habitual residence, place or work or place of alleged infringement). In Australia, this is the Office of the Australian Information Commissioner [(OAIC)](http://www.oaic.gov.au/). We will work with the appropriate regulatory and supervisory authorities, including local data protection authorities, to resolve any complaints regarding the transfer of personal information that we cannot resolve with you directly. 

Please note, you may choose to contact us in relation to a particular matter on an anonymous basis or using a pseudonym and, unless it is impracticable for us to do so or we will not be able to respond reasonably to your complaint, we will attempt to resolve your enquiry on such basis. 

###  Changes 

We may review or update our Privacy Policy from time to time. Revised versions will be available on the Website and will apply to your use of the Website, the Platform and the Services from the date of publication. Please regularly check these pages for the latest version of this notice. Any changes will take effect as soon as we publish the new Privacy Policy but there we have already collected information about you, we may take additional steps to inform you of any material changes to our Privacy Policy, including by posting on the Website, through pop-up notices or via email. 

These policies are published by and remain the property of LiveHire Ltd (ABN 59 153 266 605). 

###  Contact us 

If you've got any questions or issues with your information, please contact us at: 

LiveHire Ltd  
Level 10/461 Bourke Street  
Melbourne, VIC 3000 Email: [privacy@livehire.com](mailto:privacy@livehire.com)

###  Appendix 1 - Categories of Personal information 

Information type  |  Details of information that we typically capture   
---|---  
Individuals   
Contact Details  |  Name, address, telephone number, email address   
Employment Information  |  Resume, employment intentions, Nationality/Right to work   
Personal Information  |  Gender, date of birth, profile photo   
Marketing  |  Name, email address, interests/marketing list assignments, record of permissions or marketing objections, website data (including online account details, IP address and browser generated information)   
Customers   
Contact Details  |  Business or company name, name, work address, work email, work telephone numbers, job title, profile photo   
Marketing  |  Name, email address, interests/marketing list assignments, record of permissions or marketing objections, website data (including online account details, IP address and browser generated information)   
  
###  Appendix 2 - Legal Basis for Processing 

Activity  |  Type of information collected  |  The basis on which we use the information  |  Who we may disclose the information to   
---|---|---|---  
Individuals   
Set up a record on our systems  | 

  * Contact Details 
  * Employment Information 
  * Personal Information 

| 

  * Legitimate interests 
  * Performance of Contract with you 

| 

  * Third Party Service Providers and Other Third Parties 
  * Customers 

Provide assistance and support  | 

  * Contact Details 

| 

  * Legitimate interests 
  * Performance of Contract with you 

| 

  * Third Party Service Providers and Other Third Parties 
  * Customers 

Marketing  | 

  * Contact Details 
  * Marketing 

| 

  * Consent 
  * Legitimate interests 

| 

  * Third Party Service Providers and Other Third Parties 
  * Customers 

Comply with legal and regulatory obligations  | 

  * Contact Details 

| 

  * Legal obligation 

| 

  * Regulators 
  * Law enforcement bodies 
  * Courts 

Diversity initiatives  | 

  * Nationality 
  * Gender 

| 

  * Consent 
  * Legitimate Interests 

| 

  * Third Party Service Providers and Other Third Parties 
  * Customers 

Customers   
Manage relationships  | 

  * Contact Details 

| 

  * Legitimate interests 

| 

  * Third Party Service Providers and Other Third Parties 
  * Customers 

Administer contracts  | 

  * Contact Details 

| 

  * Performance of a contract 

| -  
Marketing  | 

  * Contact Details 
  * Marketing 

| 

  * Consent 
  * Legitimate interests 

| 

  * Third Party Service Providers and Other Third Parties 
  * Customers 

Applicable to all   
Transfer books of business  | 

  * All (where relevant to the book) 

| 

  * Legitimate interests 
  * Legal obligation 

| 

  * Courts 
  * Purchaser 
  * Professional advisors 

Sale or reorganisation of LiveHire  | 

  * All 

| 

  * Legitimate interests 
  * Legal obligation 

| 

  * Courts 
  * Purchaser 
  * Professional advisors 

###  Definitions 

**Account** means your profile and account that is held on the Platform. 

**Connection** (also **Talent Community Connection** ) means an agreement between a Worker and a Customer to be connected for potential employment opportunities and related communication. It can arise in several ways, for example through a Worker choosing to join a customer's Talent Community, applying for a job, or accepting a contact request or invitation sent from a Customer. 

**Data Controller** means a natural or legal person (such as a company) which determines the means and purposes of processing of personal information. LiveHire will be your Data Controller as it determines how it will collect personal information from you, the scope of data which will be collected, and the purposes for which it will be used. 

**Customers** means our customers and other organisations who use our Services and/or Platform from time to time. 

**Other Third Parties** means those categories of third parties in the above section ‘Information we share / disclose t other parties'. 

**Person** means any individual, company, partnership, joint venture or other legal entity or entities. 

**Personal Data** means any information (including Personal Information) capable of identifying a natural person, directly or indirectly, in particular by reference to an identification number or to one or more factors specific to their, his or her physical, physiological, mental, economic, cultural or social identity. Data is considered personal when it enables anyone to link information to a specific person, even if the person or entity holding that data cannot make that link. 

**Personal Information** has the meaning given to it in the Australian Privacy Act 1988 (Cth) as amended from time to time. 

**Platform** means the Website from time to time, and all associated software, apps, files, emails, SMS, pictures, data, hardware, technology, business systems and processes and other resources. 

**Processing** means any operation or set of operations that is performed upon Personal Data, whether or not by automatic means, including, but not limited to collection, recording, organisation, storage, access, adaptation, alteration, retrieval, consultation, use, disclosure, dissemination, making available, alignment, combination, blocking, deleting, erasure, or destruction. 

**Services** means any products, goods or services that we or any Customer or Third Party Service Provider may provide to or for you, whether or not via the Platform. 

**Sensitive Information** has the meaning given to it in the Australian Privacy Act 1988 (Cth), as amended from time to time. 

**Sensitive Personal Data** means any personal information relating to your health, criminal convictions, sex life, sexual orientation, racial or ethnic origin, political opinions, religious or philosophical beliefs, trade union membership. If you are an EU/UK individual Sensitive Personal Data will also include genetic and biometric data if collected for the purposes of uniquely identifying you. 

**Service Providers** include a range of third parties to whom we outsource certain functions of our business for our back-office, IT and professional support services (e.g. partners, service providers, contractors and agents such as IT and web support contractors, cloud service providers, finance agencies), and includes Third Party Service Providers. Some of these providers use 'cloud based' IT applications or systems, which means that your personal information will be hosted on their servers, but under our control and direction. We require all our service providers to respect the confidentiality and security of personal information. 

**Third Party Service Providers** mean our licensors, contractors, partners, suppliers and distributors, and their respective directors, and employees, including marketing partners and analysis auditors. 

**User** means a Person whose name is specified during an online registration process to create an Account on the Platform in the name of that Person, whether that Person then uses the Platform as a Customer, Worker, or on some other basis. 

**Verification** means the validation of any part of the personal information contained in a Worker's profile, CV and/or any background checks, completed by a Third Party Service Provider or LiveHire. 

**Website** means the website(s) located at [www.livehire.com](https://www.livehire.com/), [www.livehire.com.au](https://www.livehire.com.au/) and/or [www.FIFObids.com.au](https://www.fifobids.com.au/), our Blog and all other related domains and subdomains. 

**Worker** means a User who registers with the Platform as a "Worker" and uses the Platform and/or the Services primarily to search for, contact or otherwise engage with Customers or other Users for its own purposes. A Worker may include an individual user who is assigned an account on our Platform by their administrator, such as a Customer. If you are such an individual, different or additional terms may apply and your administrator may be able to access or disable your account.
